Guide to the Andrew Schultz Schultz, Jr. papers, 1932-1991
Schultz, Andrew Schultz, Jr. papers, 1932-1991
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Andrew Schultz Schultz, Jr. papers, 1932-1991
16-2-2244
Schultz, Andrew Schultz, 1913-
36 cubic ft.
Publications, correspondence, manuscripts, photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records and personal papers of Andrew Schultz, Dean of the Cornell University College of Engineering.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Andrew Schultz Schultz, Jr. served as the fifth Dean of the Cornell University College of Engineering from 1963-1972, returning as acting dean in 1978.
Schultz came to Cornell as a Mechanical Engineering student in 1932. His father was also an ME student at Cornell. Andrew received his B.S. in Administrative Engineering in 1936 and his Ph.D. in 1941. During World War II, he advanced to the rank of Lieutenant Colonel in the U.S. Army Office of the Chief of Ordnance.
He served as assistant, then full professor, in Cornell's Industrial Engineering and Administration Department before becoming department head in 1951. Schultz established Cornell's industrial engineering and administration faculty as an independent department, and he was a leader in the major transformation of industrial engineering from a qualitative to a more quantitative discipline.
As a board member of the Engineers' Council for Professional Development and member of the Commission on Education of the National Academy of Engineering, he was active in developing the professional status of engineering. He also served as chairman of the National Institutes of Health study section on accident prevention. Schultz served as vice president and director of research, and later as chairman, of the Logistics Management Institute in Washington, D.C. He was an operations analyst for the Operations Research Office of Johns Hopkins University and a consultant to the engineering advisory committee of Western Electric Co.'s Engineering Research Center in Princeton, N.J.
An avid winemaker, he was a charter member of the Ithaca Oenological Union.
Andrew Schultz passed away at his home in Ponte Vedra Beach, FL at the age of 84 on March 13, 1998.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records and personal papers of Andrew Schultz, Dean of the Cornell University College of Engineering.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schultz, Andrew Schultz, 1913-; Cornell University. College of Engineering.
Subjects:
Engineering--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Military, Correspondence, Personal Papers, Photographs: Boxes 1, 30
Series II. Faculty and Committee Meetings, Minutes, Memos: BoxES 1, 11, 13
Series III. Industrial Engineering Students, Curriculum, Miscellaneous: Boxes 2, 11, 13, 15, 16, 17, 18, 20, 22, 35, 36, 37
Series IV. Graduate Student Papers, Miscellaneous Industrial Engineering Papers: Boxes 3, 11, 18, 20, 21, 22, 26, 27, 28
Series V. Research and Reports: Box 4, 14, 18, 21
Series VI. Class of 1936 Reunion Apparel: Box 5
Series VII. Biographical Material and Correspondence: Box 6
Series VIII. Course Material: Institutes and Programs: Box 7
Series IX. Institutes and Programs: Boxes 7, 16, 22, 29
Series X. Committees: Boxes 7, 8, 11
Series XI. Budget Matters: Boxes 8, 11
Series XII. Engineering College: Reports, Proposals, Rosters, Photographs: Boxes 8, 11, 13, 19, 20, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35
Series XIII. Development and Corporate Relations: Boxes 8, 9, 13, 18
Series XIV. Slides: Box 10
Series XV. Mapcase items
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Military, Correspondence, Personal Papers, Photographs (Boxes 1, 30)
  - Military - Leave and Special Orders, 1936-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Military - Correspondence, 1939-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Military - Official Papers, Promotions, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Military - Reserve Officer Papers, 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Military - Reserve Training, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Military - Active Duty, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Employment Search, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - H, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - O, 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - P, 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Statler Club, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Midaswell Investment Club, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, ca. 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Class of 1936 Reunion Photos (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Book Correspondence, 1960 (Box 30)
  - Kimball & Kimball Correspondence, 1953 (Box 30)
- Series II. Faculty and Committee Meetings, Minutes, Memos (Boxes 1, 11, 13)
  - Cornell Pamphlets, Programs, Publications, ca. 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Staff Memos, 1948-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Social Security, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Committee on the Library Building, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Committees on Economy and Economic Status of the Faculty, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Economic Status of the Faculty, 1952-1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Committee on Economy - Engineering, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Size of the University Committee, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Faculty Meetings, 1947-1955 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Faculty Council/Meetings, 1956-1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Engineering Faculty Meetings, Policies, 1950-1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Engineering Faculty Meetings, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cornell Co-op Invoices, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Faculty committees, 1940-1942 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - EEngineering College curricula, 1931-1934 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - John Bangs and engineering administration, 1961-1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Industrial engineering, 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Industrial engineering: budget, 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 18-22)
  - Industrial engineering: personnel, 1963-1972 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Planning projection, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Engineering College administration, parts 1-2, 1964-1973 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Legislation, policies, precedents, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Industrial engineering: syllabi, outlines, 1953-1957 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Continuing education, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Policies for deans, 1957-1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Deans' Council: current topics, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Deans' Council: topics, 1968-1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Deans' Council: organization, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Dean's: promotion, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Development, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Directors' meetings, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Public disruption, parts 1-2, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - Faculty Council minutes, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Draft Engineering Manpower Committee, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - President's Commission, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Engineering College Council (E.C.C.), 1976-1979 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - ECC, 1962-1980 (Box 13, Folder 15-17)
  - Equipment needs, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Faculty salary study, 1956-1968 (Box 13, Folder 19-22)
  - Mechanical Engineering Study Group, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 32)
- Series III. Industrial Engineering Students, Curriculum, Miscellaneous (Boxes 2, 11, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22, 35, 36, 37)
  - Cornell Placement Service - Recruiting, Faculty, 1949-1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Placement Service - Corporate Recruiting, 1949-1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Corporate Recruiting - Employment Information, 1949-1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Plant Managers Conference, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Engineering Curriculum, 1951-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Industrial Engineering Curriculum (II), 1951-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Industrial Engineering Curriculum Publications (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Engineering Curriculum Changes, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Freshmen Orientation Lectures, 1955-1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Summer School, 1947-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Industrial Engineering Seminars, 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Systems Engineering Management Course, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - CU Engineering Policy, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Fifth-Year Engineering Project Correspondence, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Research Projects, 1948-1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Research Projects and Reports, 1955-1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Undergraduate Project Papers, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Research Proposals, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Research Ideas, 1952-1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Computing at Cornell, 1956-1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Kappa Tau Chi (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Operations Research Office Log, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Johns Hopkins Operations Research Office, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Work for IBM, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Work for Western Electric, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Digital Systems Simulation - Cornell Research Simulator Project, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Reports on "Estimating Applied Research and Engineering Work Time, ca. 1959 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - System Development Corporation (SDC) Papers, Reports, Misc., 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Engineers' Council for Professional Development (ECPD) Reports on Curriculum at University of Connecticut, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Industrial Engineering Department and Curriculum (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bangs, John, Engineering Administration (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Industrial engineering curricula, 1963-1965 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Alumni & curricula, 1975-1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum notes, 1953-1955 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum studies, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum planning and approval, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum: basic studies, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum: basic industrial engineering, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum: basic industrial engineering, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Curriculum Committee, mechanical engineering curriculum, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Curriculum: industrial engineering, 1967-1977 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Industrial engineering 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Personnel (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Syllabi, Outlines, Administration for Department of Industrial Engineering (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Fleischman, H. T.: project 1978 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Cornell student exchange brochures (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Intersession 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Electives study 1963 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Mechanical science & engineering memos 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - LMI 1970-1071 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Science Foundation correspondence 1973 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - N.I.H. 1964-1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Newport News 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Council for the Advancement of Industrial Research and Development 1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Press releases 1973 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Olmstead Study 1974 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - S. I. Handling Systems 1961-1980 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - S. I. statement to stockholders 1959-1971 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Singapore 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Western Electric Engineering Training source materials 1957-1958 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 231 Western Electric 1963-1977 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Melvin A. Zurn 1967 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Graduate Engineering Training Program 1957 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Work sampling 1951-1956 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Production engineering 1954-1963 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Kayser's Standard Data (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Engineering and Economics 1955-1967 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - 410 Computing 1, 2, 3 1975 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - OR 9310 course information 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Computing 10, 11, 12, 13 1975-1977 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - OR 9410 Computing Problems (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Registration process project 1976 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Computing problems, 4, 5, 6 1975 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Computing problems, 7, 8, 9 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - IOR 410 A10 1975-1977 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Layout 1963 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Work measurement 1977 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Methods 1957-1975 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - OR 9410 final examination 1974-1978 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Replacement theory 1954-1955 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Dynamic programming 1961 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Survey of machine replacement analyses 1956 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - QC sampling process evaluation (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - CPM project management (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous class materials (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Job evaluation (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - ISD 9511: Jerry Jenson course paper 1970 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Introduction to material handling 1966 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Flexible Manufacturing System, Japan 1979-1982 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - OR 9512, OR 9310, OR 9311 Quality control: course materials 1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - OR 9551 Engineering Economics, parts 1-6 1974-1977 (Box 16, Folder 2-7)
  - OR 9551 Engineering Economics, grades 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Course materials: Financial budget planning 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - OR 9551: stock market strategy 1973-1978 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Course materials: regression analysis (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - OR 9310 & OR 9311: prediction methods (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - E 161, IE 232, OR 9310, 9350: engineering and economy 1973-1976 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - OR 9310: dynamic programming problems (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Course materials: statistical approaches to tolerances (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - OR 9551: appraisal 1974 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - OR 9303: manufacturing progress function (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Course materials: bank credit and borrowing 1975 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - I.O.R. 551: papers (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Course materials: industrial engineering program Pennsylvania State University 1963 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Course materials: industrial market research 1962 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Corning Glass Works project 1960 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Corning Glass Works 1961 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - European Productivity Agency 1959 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Science Advisory Committee, Andover 1959 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Operations research 1959 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - International Cooperation Administration, Mexico 1959 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Course materials: quality control 1950 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Course materials: statistical methods and military standard 1950 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Jackson and Moreland accounts 1938 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Hollister inventory tests 1941-1948 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Pre-War studies 1940-1945 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Psych - tables of raw data 1931-1936 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Psych - final data 1931-1948 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Psych study summaries 1931-1936 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Psych - College Board 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - ASEE (Engineering Education) - engineering inventory project 1947 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Psych - Post-War test results 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Psych - University Test Service 1946-1948 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Other studies (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Grades, college and university 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Alberto's [Arádz] project 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Operation Andy (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Operation Andy: Appendix C, details of calculations (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Statistics notebook: Andrew Schultz (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Data, figures, papers 1955 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Senior critique (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Operation Andy: Appendix B, details of calculations (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Summary outline (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Quartermaster study proposals 1956-1957 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Economic comparison of alternative conditions 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Economic development abroad 1956 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Corning Glass Works analysis 1957 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Building and equipment costs: apple and pear packing 1952 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Alberto B. Arádz journal 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Post-war technical assistance to foreign countries project [Arádz] (2 copies) 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Arádz project 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Arádz project: Alberto reference draft 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Arádz project, part 1 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Pilot study [Arádz] 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Advisory Committee meeting 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Committee minutes 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Engineering the engineering job, J. M. Brown 1952 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Engineering effectiveness study, meeting #5 1960 (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - Hand written notes 1960 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Program report to W. A. Welsh 1961 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Allentown study 1961 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Meeting the New Engineering Challenge, parts 1&2 (leader's guide) 1961 (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
  - Brochure for participants 1961 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - For supervisors only 1961 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Motivations and working relations of scientists and engineers 1959 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Meeting the new engineering challenge brochures 1961 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Report to engineers 1961 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Typed records and reports 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Work sampling study 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Worker study 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Report on better use of engineering talent 1952 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Research bulletins 1956-1959 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Panel discussion: F. E. Hanson (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Turret Lathe Machine data 1959 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Pilot visit M.I.T. 1960 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Engineering effectiveness study memo 1960 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Bibliographies 1960 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Meeting announcements 1960 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Future topics (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - CWEPE-N union 1960 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Blank surveys, notes (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Course Materials - OR551 (Box 20)
  - Yardwide idleness survey 1973 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Yardwide work samples 1972 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Idleness study data worksheets 1973 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Yardwide idleness study materials and results 1973 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Construction schedule, parts 1-2 1971-1973 (Box 22, Folder 5-6)
  - Shipboard information system, vols. 1-2 1968 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Contract charges and claims 1973 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - IOR410 - Industrial Systems Analysis, 1974 (Box 35)
  - OR&IE410 - Industrial Systems Analysis, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Computerized Machine Replacement Service, 1973 (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Intro/Background/Basic Concepts (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Product Design (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Flow Processes (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Anatomy of Productive Systems (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Process Layout of Department (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Industrial Systems Analysis, 1978 (Box 35)
  - 9310 - PLT Location (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 1A: Method, Design (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Layout Process (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 16: Psych and Physiology, 1974 (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 19: Time Standards (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 20: Standard Data (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 21: Work Sampling (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 22: Wage Incentives (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Various Material (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Various Material (cont.) (Box 35)
  - 9551 - Prelim 1, 1978 (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 23: Quality Control Sampling (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 24 & 25: Quality Control Charts (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 25 & 26: Quality Control Attributes (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Lecture 26 & 27: Project Control (Box 35)
  - 9310 - Exams (Box 36)
  - 9310 - Prelim, 1978 (Box 36)
  - 9310 - Lecture 18 / Prelim 2, 1975-77 (Box 36)
  - 9410 - Final, 1978 (Box 36)
  - 9310 - Various Course Material (Box 36)
  - Methods & Forms 800 & Up (Box 36)
  - Methods & Forms 800 & Up (Box 36)
  - Methods & Forms 500-700, 1954 (Box 36)
  - Methods & Forms 500-700 (Box 36)
  - Methods & Forms 200-400 (Box 36)
  - Methods & Forms 200-400 (Box 36)
  - OR&IE 3242 - Course Material (Box 36)
  - Proposal for the Cornell College of Engineering Instructional Television System, 1972 (Box 36)
  - Report: Cornell Workshops on the Major Issues of a National Energy Research and Development Program, 1973 (Box 36)
  - 3270 (Production Engineering) - Course Material (Box 36)
  - 3270 (Production Engineering) - Course Material (Box 36)
  - Report: "Industrial Engineering and Administration at Cornell: The Field" (Box 36)
  - Industrial Engineering and Administration at Cornell: Various Material (Box 36)
  - Minutes of Curriculum Review Committee, 1953 (Box 36)
  - Engineering Curricula, 1952 (Box 36)
  - Study of the Performance of Cornell Undergraduate Engineers, 1948 (Box 36)
  - Report: "Learning Curves and Learnin gTime Projection Methods as Used in Industry," 1961 (Box 36)
  - IBM Accounting: Machine Functions, 1960 (Box 36)
  - Curtiss-Wright QC Handbook (Box 36)
  - Various IE Reports, 1958-61 (Box 36)
  - Various IE Reports, 1957-58 (Box 36)
  - Various IE Reports, 1951 (Box 36)
  - OR&IE 3254 Student Reports (Box 36)
  - Enrollment and Graduation Staff (Box 37)
  - Various Industrial Engineering Material (Box 37)
  - Employment / Job Placement Reports (Box 37)
  - Periodicals - Engineering Degrees, 1968-69 (Box 37)
  - Reports - Recipients of Engineering Degrees, 1969, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Survey: Engineering Enrollments, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Engineering and Technical Enrollments, 1968 (Box 37)
  - Engineers Joint Council Reports - Engineering Degrees (Box 37)
  - Standardization Papers - Drafts, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Department of Defense - Defense Standardization Manual (Box 37)
  - DoD Report - Management Analysis of the Cataloging Division (Box 37)
  - DoD Accelerated Item Reduction Program, 1954-59 (Box 37)
  - DoD Memos, 1962-63 (Box 37)
  - Armed Forces Supply Support Center (AFSSC) Evaluation of Defense Standardization Program, 1958 (Box 37)
  - Study: Parts Specification Management for Reliability, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Military Supply Standard and Supply Management (Box 37)
  - DoD Standardization Program: Standardization Plan for Connectors Electrical (Box 37)
  - NSIA Specification Simplification Committee, 1961 (Box 37)
- Series IV. Graduate Student Papers, Miscellaneous Industrial Engineering Papers (Boxes 3, 18, 20, 21, 22, 26, 27, 28)
  - Graduate Placement Statistics, 1952-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Student Statistics, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Student Records, 1952-1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Student Policies, Misc., 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Matters, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Fellowships, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Fellowships, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Undergraduate Matters, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Departmental Matters, 1947-1953, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Departmental Research, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Research Support, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Regulations Regarding Soviet Students, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Justine S. Evans Memorial Fund - Economics in Engineering, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 3261 Man-Machine Charts (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Production Scheduling and Capital Expenditure (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Western Electric Courses, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Labor Relations/Education Residential Study, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Publicity, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Engineering Standards, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - A. G. Ashcroft Talk at Cornell, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Residency Program, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - American Institute of Industrial Engineers (AIIE) Seminar, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Industrial Engineering Publications, Pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - English education at Cornell: proposal 1965 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Industrial engineering: curriculum 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The scientific mind and the management mind 1959 (Box 18, Folder 23)